Some of the modules in the Python Standard Library have a lot in them.
بعض الوحدات النمطية في مكتبة Python القياسية على الكثير من الأشياء.
In order to manage the code better,
من أجل إدارة الكود بشكل أفضل،
they're split down into sub-modules that are contained within a package.
تم تقسيمها إلى وحدات نمطية فرعية موجودة داخل رزمة.
A package is simply a module that contains sub-modules.
الرزمة هي ببساطة وحدة نمطية تحتوي على وحدات نمطية فرعية.
A sub-module is specified with the usual dot notation.
يتم تحديد وحدة نمطية فرعية بخط متقطع اعتيادي.
For example, the OS module,
على سبيل المثال، وحدة OS النمطية،
which is useful for dealing with file systems has a sub-module os.path,
وهي مفيدة للتعامل مع أنظمة الملفات، لديها وحدة نمطية فرعية تدعى os.path،
which is used specifically for dealing with path names.
والتي تستخدم للتعامل مع أسماء مسارات الملفات بشكل خاص.
Modules that are sub-modules are specified by
يتم تحديد الوحدات النمطية التي هي وحدات نمطية فرعية
the package name and then the sub-module name separated by a dot.
عن طريق اسم الرزمة، ثم اسم الوحدة النمطية الفرعية مفصولة باستخدام نقطة.
You can import the sub-module os.path like this.
يمكنك استيراد الوحدة النمطية الفرعية os.path هكذا.
You can then use the objects from the sub-module in the usual way.
يمكنك بعدها استخدام الكائنات من الوحدة النمطية الفرعية بالشكل المعتاد.
However, this syntax for importing will only work for sub-modules.
لكن بناء الجملة هذا في الاستيراد لن يعمل سوى مع وحدات نمطية فرعية.
You cannot import a function from a module in this way.
لا يمكنك استيراد دالة من وحدة نمطية بهذه الطريقة.
If you want to use other parts of the OS module two,
إن أردت استخدام أجزاء أخرى من وحدة OS النمطية أيضاً،
you could import OS instead and everything in the os.path will still be accessible.
فيمكنك استيراد OS بدلاً من ذلك، وسيبقى كل شيء في os.path متاحاً.
Sometimes, naming can be a point of confusion when working with modules.
قد تكون التسمية أحياناً محط ارتباك أثناء العمل مع الوحدات النمطية.
For example, a module might be named after
على سبيل المثال، فقد تسمى وحدة نمطية
one of the important classes or functions within it.
على اسم إحدى الفئات أو الدوال المهمة التي في داخلها.
In this case, you will need to think carefully about your import statements.
ستحتاج في هذه الحال للتفكير ملياً في عبارات الاستيراد.
This imports the datetime class from the datetime module.
سيستورد هذا فئة Datetime من وحدة Datetime النمطية.
Note that after this, using datetime,
لاحظ أن بعد هذا، استخدام Datetime
will refer to the datetime class, not the module.
سيشير إلى فئة Datetime، وليس الوحدة النمطية.